我不做猎人了  我找到了一些东西
I don't hunt anymore. I found something.
-她叫什么  -艾米利亚
- What was her name? - Amelia!
迪恩  我不当猎人的那一年
Dean, the year that I took off,
我拥有了我从没有过的东西
I had something I've never had.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday!
正常人的生活
A normal life.
你一直在炼狱
You were in Purgatory?
让我觉得纯粹
It felt pure.
你怎么逃出来的
Well, how'd you get out?
-我有你想要的东西 -什么东西
- I got something you need. - Yeah, what's that?
我带你找到门
I show you the door,
你把我的灵魂带过去
you hump my soul to the other side.
我们成功了  兄弟
We made it, brother.
那小卡呢  他也在那里吗
What about Cass? Was he there?
他在下面出了点事
Something happened to him down there.
没有你我不走
I'm not leaving here without you.
凯文・谭  上帝的先知
Kevin Tran, Prophet of the Lord.
名号不错
It does have a nice ring to it.
凯文
Kevin!
-上面说什么  -劝我们别去追
- Hey. What's it say? - That we shouldn't come looking,
既然我们没了石碑  凯文觉得我们不需要他了
and since we lost the tablet, Kevin figures we don't need him.
但是克劳力还用得上他
Yeah, but Crowley still does.
如今
华盛顿州  伊格尔港
你好  昆丁
Hello, Quentin.
本尼
Benny.
不  不可能是你
No, I-it -- it can't be you.
我能理解你的困惑
I get the confusion.
你心里最清楚  我绝对是死翘翘了
You of all people knew I was really, truly dead.
毕竟当时你还摁着我的腿呢
After all, you held down my legs, didn't you?
而老爸则让索兰托把我的头锯下来
When the old man told Sorento to saw off my head.
他在哪
Where is he?
你不是吧
Are you serious?
你真以为我会告诉你他在哪吗
Did you really think I'd tell you where he is?
其实  我就希望你不告诉我
Well, I guess I was kind of hoping you wouldn't.
不过  我也可以带你去找他
On the other hand, I might show you where he is.
但我们得先剁掉你的四肢
After me and my boys take off your hands and feet.
可别为我这么大费周章啊
Well, don't go through all that trouble on my account.
拜托
Please.
你从上帝的屁股底下爬出来
You go and crawl your way out of God's ass
就是来坐旋转木马的吗
for another ride on the merry-go-round?
老爸肯定想亲眼看到你
The old man's gonna want to see this for himself.
他们也许有本事杀掉我
Well, they might be able to kill me.
这没什么
And that's all right.
我很清楚我死后会去哪里
'Cause if they do, I know exactly where I'm going...
还有在那里会遇到什么人
and who I'll see when I get there.
《凶鬼恶灵》第八季 第五集
俄勒冈州  伊尼德
血脉兄弟
他这是耍我们两次了
Well, that is twice that he's burned us.
-你丢人吧  -你少来
- Shame on you. - No, no, no, no.
是我说他给我们下了套
I'm the one who said he set us up.
不对  你说的是
No, you said,
"不知这是不是凯文的圈套"
"I wonder if Kevin is setting us up,"
之后你就开始说那些无聊的技术问题了
and then you started in with the -- the techno babble.
那是在上上个州的时候
That was like two states ago.
好吧  随便你
Yeah, well, whatever.
不管怎样
Either way,
这个房间的付款人也是凯文的一个假身份
that's another room billed to one of Kevin's false credit I.D.s.
而且汽车旅馆今天刷过他的卡
And the motel ran his number today.
就好像他真的入住了一样
Just like he actually checked in?
是啊
Yes.
这孩子就像是雨人
Kid's like Rain Man.
出自电影《雨人》  雨人是对数字十分敏感的自闭症患者
电影中有一段是雨人在赌场数牌赢了一大笔钱
他就像个会"数"信用卡的讨厌鬼
He's like a crappy little credit-card-counting...
犯罪天才型雨人
Criminal prodigy Rain Man.
他可是跳级生呢
Well, he was in advanced placement.
闭嘴
Shut up.
那个小白痴什么时候能不躲我们了
When's that little idiot gonna stop running from us?
不知道  迪恩
I don't know, Dean.
你当时可真要杀他妈妈呢
I mean, you did try to kill his mother.
我那是想杀死克劳力
I was trying to kill Crowley, okay?
只不过他当时附身在凯文妈妈身上
Who happened to be wearing Kevin's mother at the time.
这不是一回事
Well, there's a difference.
凯文显然不这么看
Apparently not to Kevin.
大概因为  哦对  那是他妈
Oh, I know. Maybe because -- oh, yeah, -- it's his mother.
等会儿再说
Hold that thought.
还是算了  你就打消那个念头吧
No, actually, you know what? Don't hold that thought.
你好
Hello?
稍等  信号不好
Uh, hang on. There's not enough bars.
本尼
Benny?
好啊  迪恩
Hey, Dean.
你有空吗
You, um -- you got a minute?
我搞砸了  老兄
Afraid I messed up, buddy.
你做了什么
What did you do?
不  老兄  不是那样
No, man, not like that.
再说一次  你对付了几个
I'm sorry. You took on how many?
-你疯了吗  -别这样
- Are you crazy? - Hey.
问题在于  我的腿有点不灵便了
See, the thing is, my legs -- they ain't working so good.
这里有个
There's, uh...
燃油驳船离得不远
a fuel barge not too far from here.
我肯定能慢慢爬过去
I'm pretty sure I can make it at a slow crawl.
但是我想再让你帮我个忙
I was kind of hoping maybe I could ask you for one more favor?
那是什么意思
And -- and what exactly is that supposed to mean,
-什么叫你必须走  -哪个词没听懂
- you've got to go? - Which words are giving you trouble?
我们手头有活儿呢  记得吗  迪恩
We're on the case, remember, Dean?
温彻斯特家的圣杯
The Winchester holy grail,
"永远关上地狱之门"大计
"Shut the gates of hell forever" case.
当然  但是为了关上地狱之门
Sure are. But in order to close the Gates of Hell,
我们需要先知  没错吧
we need our Prophet, am I right?
第一步  找到凯文・谭
So step one -- find Kevin Tran.
他不在这里啊
Well, he ain't here.
但他把我们引到这儿
But he wanted us to be,
那我们肯定是在他能把我们
which means we're probably as far away from him
甩得最远的地方了
as he could possibly put us.
那么第二步  找到凯文・谭
So step two -- find Kevin Tran.
介意我拿走三角巧克力吗
You mind if I take the Toblerone?
等等  迪恩  你来真的
Wait. Dean, seriously?
线索断了  但是房费已经付了
Hey, the trail is dead, but the room is paid for.
你还有调查要做
You got some research to do,
而我要处理一点私人的破事儿
and I got some personal crap I got to take care of.
-就这样吧  -什么叫"私人的"
- That's all. - What does that mean -- "Personal"?
你中风了吗
Did you have a stroke?
话都听不懂了
Vocabulary?
私人的  就是说我一成年人个人的...
Personal, as in my own grown-up personal --
怎么说呢  就是破事儿
I don't know -- crap.
-见鬼  -怎么了  萨姆
- Damn it -- - What, Sam?
别忘了  你休了一年没做事
Last I counted, you took a year off from the job.
我只需要休一天
I need a day.
普林斯顿大学
你个卑鄙的兔子  谭先生
You are a wascally wabbit, Mr. Tran.
卡斯卡迪亚信用合作社
这叫关心
Concerned.
不是跟踪  是关心
Not stalking...concerned.
艾米利亚・理查德森
埃弗雷特  老兄  你还在上班啊
Everett. Hey, buddy, you still on duty?
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
你父亲怎么样了
How's your dad?
对新食谱不太适应
He's kind of having it rough on the new regimen.
吃什么都吐
Can't keep anything down.
真糟糕
That sucks.
是啊
Yeah.
这样  我打算再住一周
Listen, um, I'm gonna stay on another week, okay?
不过要用这张卡
But I need you to run it on this card,
上次登记的那张刚刚注销了
'cause I just canceled the one you had on file.
好  没问题
Okay, sure.
以为这会儿你该走了呢
Figured you'd have moved on by now.
那个  我目前没工作
Right. Well, I'm -- I'm kind of between jobs.
再说狗狗周二还有个后续手术
plus, uh, Dog has a surgery follow-up on Tuesday.
是啊  这狗被你弄得挺惨
Yeah, you really messed up that dog.
可不是  多谢帮忙
Right. Uh, thanks for that.
那东西就这样
Oh, yeah, it's all that thing does --
漏水  嗡嗡响  浪费我们的电费
piss, moan, and eat up money we ain't got.
你有工具吗
Well, you got any tools?
你要是能修好它  就不用出去找工作了
Hell, if you can fix it, you don't need to go and look for a job.
在这儿干就行
You got one here.
本尼
Benny!
Benny?
情况不妙
Not lookin' good.
去你的
Up yours.
你...
Wow. You, uh...
气色不错
look okay.
正在恢复
Getting there.
老兄  你刚才就跟废了一样
Dude, you were double-hamstrung.
稍作休息  再来几包AB阴性血
Yeah, well, a little rest, a half a cooler full of AB-negative...
只要没缺胳膊少腿  大部分伤都能痊愈
most wounds short of an amputation will mend up...
吸血鬼就这样
vampirically speaking.
很快我就能完全恢复了
I'll be 100% before you know it.
谢谢你  兄弟
Thank you, brother.
本尼  怎么回事
Benny, what's going on?
你该干的都干完了  迪恩
Oh, your work here is done, Dean.
能帮的都帮了
You already saved the day.
我有我的事情  你有你的...
You know, I got my, uh, deal, and you got --
怎么说来着
what'd you call it?
家族事业
A family business?
本尼
Benny.
到底怎么回事
What's going on?
你的朋友义气真要命啊
You and that whole "friend" thing, man.
迪恩  我得承认他确实有两下子
Well, I got to admit, Dean -- he's got his strong points,
但也太惹眼了
but holy hell if he ain't a magnet.
没找到小卡之前
Well, before we found Cass,
你还嫌我的人肉味儿引人注意呢
you said it was my humanity that was drawing too much attention.
你也一样
Yeah, that too.
我想我们暂时安全了
Well, I think we're clear for the moment.
玄学上讲来真是个有趣的问题
It does present a curious curl in the metaphysics, doesn't it?
在妖怪天堂里杀妖怪
If you murder a monster in monster heaven,
它们会去哪呢
where does it go?
这就是跟我们一起上路的疯姨妈
And this is the crazy aunt I want to take on the road?
我不是你姨妈
I am not your aunt.
什么  真的吗
What? Really?
我和你的血族没有潜在亲缘关系
I have no possible relationship to your sibling offspring.
你开我心呢
Now, you're kidding me.
你们俩个折磨死我了
Oh, you two are killing me.
我得同意吸血鬼的说法  迪恩
I have to agree with the vampire, Dean.
冒险带炽天使逃出炼狱...
The risk of crossing Purgatory with a seraph --
相当不明智
it's...less than strategic,
况且我们又没理由相信
and certainly when we have no reason to believe
我能通过你们要走的那扇门
that I can pass through the door that you're headed for.
你看  你是深陷炼狱的
You see, you're an intact,
完好无损活生生的人类
living human being stuck in Purgatory's craw.
这个空间想把你赶出去
This dimension wants to spit you out,
这就是我们逃出生天的原动力
which is exactly what's gonna power our escape pod.
我自己肯定也能混出去
Now, I'm pretty sure I can squeeze through, too,
因为不论如何  除了尖牙和吸血之乐
because, after all, you take away the fangs and the fun,
我也曾经是个人类
I was born human, too.
可是...
But...
我想我恐怕不行
I don't think it would work for me.
听到他说的了吗  迪恩
You hear what he's telling you, Dean?
你哥们他说...
Your buddy is saying --
给我听着  你这吸血成瘾的不死族
Listen to me, you undead blood junkie,
魔法对我有效  计划我说了算
I'm the one with the mojo. I'm the one with the plan.
小卡
Cass...
我们一定会想办法让你穿过那扇门
we're gonna shove your ass back through the eye of that needle
在所不辞
if it kills all three of us.
不用说  我对此很不满意
Obviously, I'm less than comfortable with that.
你还这么死脑筋  真让我倍感安慰
Well, it's good to know you're still dumb as ever.
有些事是不会变的
Yeah, well, some things never change.
你怎么跟同类挥起砍刀来了
Now, why are you getting into machete fights with your own kind?
昆丁  我来找的那家伙
Quentin, the one I came for?
我们原是一个巢穴的
We were in the same nest.
我在追杀转化我的那个吸血鬼  我的创造者
I'm hunting the vampire who turned me, my maker.
不要误会
Well, now, don't get me wrong.
我支持你杀他  可是为什么
I'm down with the hunting, but, uh...why?
先下手为强
Kill him before he kills me...
免得我再遭殃
again.
棒极了
Awesome.
如果你还没下班
Uh, if you're still on the clock,
118的女士说她的水槽堵了
lady in 118 says the sink's backed up.
怎么回事
What the hell?
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我就知道你这人不对劲
I knew there was something off about you,
那堆吓人的陆海军装备  还有鬓角
with your creepy Army-Navy and your sideburns --
停下
Stop, stop.
我在帮你修水槽
Um, I'm fixing your sink.
什么
What?
我和昆丁是老朋友了
Quentin and I went way back --
他是老爸最喜欢的一个  仅次于我
one of the old man's favorites, next to me, it turns out.
听听这个
Listen to this.
"水瓶座纪元二号  0800"
"Age of Aquarius II, 0800,"
后面还有数字  都划掉了
and then there's some other numbers all crossed out.
还有些奇怪的名字  "大美人鱼"
Some other weird names here, too -- the Big Mermaid,
"红心大战"  也都划掉了
Solitaire -- it's all crossed out,
除了这一个  "幸运玛拉"
except this one -- the Lucky Myra.
是游艇
Yachts.
游艇的名字  幸运玛拉  水瓶座纪元二号
Names of yachts -- Lucky Myra, Age of Aquarius II.
你看这个  "洄见"多了三点水
Look at this one -- Sea You Later, spelled s-e-a.
该懂了吧
I mean, come on.
这是出航时间
So, then these are launch times.
还有目的地
And what -- destinations?
没错  但这些艇都不会靠港了
Mm-hmm. Except none of them ever get there.
幸运玛拉昨天下午起航
The Lucky Myra left yesterday afternoon.
我可以保证它已经遭袭了
I guarantee you it's already been hit.
"遭袭"是什么意思
What do you mean, "hit"?
强行登船  焚毁  葬身海底
Boarded, burned, and buried at sea.
这是我们巢穴用餐的方式
My nest -- that's how we fed...
一向如此
How we always fed.
我们养着一只小舰队  大概有六艘船
We kept a tight little fleet, maybe a half-dozen boats.
外表并不招摇  只是普通游船
Nothing ostentatious, just pleasure craft.
我航行的里程都够绕美洲十圈了
I must have circled the Americas 10 times during my tour.
有人专门扮成外乡人  在港口游荡
A few of us would act as stringers and patrol the harbors,
寻找合适的目标
looking for the right-size target --
那些驶向很远的港口的豪华游轮
fat, rich yachts going to far-off ports.
记录下游轮的名字和目的地
Take down the boat's name and destination,
再用无线电通知水上的同伴
radio it to the crew in the water.
然后我们就...
And then we just, uh...
让海水淹没我们的罪行
let the ocean swallow up all our sins.
你们是吸血鬼海盗
Vampire pirates?
原来你们是干这个的
That's what you guys are?
吸血海盗
Vampirates.
我们一起干了这么多年
You know, all the years we ran together,
居然从没有人想到过
I can't believe nobody ever thought of that.
你说什么啊  这个很容易想到啊
What do you mean? It's like the third thing you say.
才不是呢
No, it isn't.
好吧  你的创造者
All right, so, y-your maker
准备在这附近觅食对吗
is set up to feed around here, right?
我们该怎么找
Well, what are we looking for?
他生活一向很有范儿
Well, he likes to live in style.
他通常合法租下房屋
He usually rents legitimately.
偏远而临海的地方
Always remote, always coastal.
可能是个小岛
So an island, maybe?
这是有线电视收费单
You got a cable bill here.
昆丁还包月了美国棒球联盟
Hmm. Quentin's got the NFL package.
普兰提斯岛
Prentiss Island.
听说过吗
Heard of it?
是的
Oh, yeah.
既然你是创造者的心头肉
Yeah, so, if you were your maker's favorite,
他为什么要杀死你
why did he kill you?
当你被转化的时候
When you get turned,
就像你重新生在了一个吸血鬼巢穴中
it's like you're reborn into a vampire nest.
你的创造者就是你的全部
Your maker -- he means everything to you.
你会开始相信他就是上帝
I mean, you really start believing he's God.
如果你的创造者也是这么想的话
Now, if your maker happens to believe the same thing, well...
就成了问题了
See how that could be a pickle.
你非要现在吸那个东西吗
you really have to do that? I mean, right now?
对不起  兄弟
I'm sorry, brother.
我感觉好多了  但还在恢复
I'm better, but I'm still on the mend.
好吧
Right.
我们的父亲  他嫉妒心很重
Anyway...our father -- he was a jealous God.
他让家族成员住在一起
He kept the family together
在海上漂泊  远离外面的世界
but kept us apart from the rest of the world, always at sea.
我做事一向以家族为先
I always did what was best for the nest...
直到我遇见了她
till I met her.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
安德莉亚・科莫斯
Andrea Kormos.
她真美
Beautiful.
那种无以言表的美  你懂吗
I mean, words don't even cut it, you know?
希腊的名门之后
Greek, heiress.
不是吧
Come on.
她驾一艘单桅帆船前往加那利群岛
She was sailing a 42-foot sloop to the Canary Islands.
我本该把她的目的地告诉我的同伴
Now, I should have called her boat's destination in to my crew,
但我却跟她上了船
but instead, I joined her on it.
真的吗
Seriously?
这算是什么三俗的桥段啊
Was Fabio on the cover of that paperback?
我的生活从此因她而变  迪恩
My life changed when she entered it, Dean.
在那之前我所做的一切
Everything I had been or done up to that point just...
似乎都消失了
seemed to vanish...
只剩下了我和她
Into what we had become together.
我们找到了真爱  伙计
I mean... We found it, man.
最后  我们在路易斯安那定居
Eventually, we settled in Louisiana.
然后有天晚上  我们回到家
And then one night, we were coming home,
老爸就在那儿等我
and the old man -- he was just there.
还有我的旧友昆丁  索兰托
Quentin, Sorento, my oldest nestmates.
直到那天晚上我才明白
It was only that night I understood
我的离开  在他看来多么不可饶恕
what a crime it was to him -- me leaving him.
他们把我按在地上  接着斩首
They pinned me down, and they beheaded me.
我看到的最后一幕
The last thing I saw
就是他咬破安德莉亚的喉咙
was the old man tearing out Andrea's throat.
报复不就是这样吗
Well, that's what payback's all about -- am I right?
到码头了
Docks are up ahead.
应该能找到能用的小船
Should be able to find a dinghy to use.
快到了
We're close.
我在抓吸血鬼  老巢在普兰提斯岛
想到什么了吗
Remind you of anything?
删除
回到这个世界突然感觉怪怪的
It's weird being back -- in the world, I mean.
不是吗
Isn't it?
是啊
Sure as hell is.
你是怎么面对这一切的
I mean, what do you do with it all?
所有这一切
All the -- all the everything?
我都不知道这世界是不是真的
Hell, I don't even know if this world is real,
我是不是真的
if I'm real.
听我说
Hey, listen to me.
我十分清楚这种心态的后果
I see what happens down that rabbit hole, okay?
我们是真的
We're real.
本尼  这一切都是真的
Benny, this is real.
要活下去必须这么想  懂了吗
It's the only way to play this game, you get me?
该走了  本尼
Time to move, Benny.
老爸的大键琴
The old man's harpsichord.
本尼
Benny!
不
No.
不  不
No, no.
本尼
Benny?
安德莉亚
Andrea.
傻子
Idiot.
想让我再杀你一次吗
Gonna make me do this all over again, aren't you?
你好  索兰托
Hello, Sorento.
他转化了你
He turned you.
现在有点忙
Little busy right now.
迪恩二号备用手机
This is Dean's other, other cell,
你知道该怎么做
so you must know what to do.
德州驾照  艾米利亚・理查德森
你就是干这个的
So, that's what you do?
跟踪无助的妇女
You stalk helpless women
闯入她们的房间然后修她们的水管
and you break into their motel room and you fix their plumbing?
你为什么要修我的水槽
Why are you fixing my sink?
因为有人丢了一大堆酸橙进去塞住了水管
Well, because somebody jammed about 800 limes down the drain...
损坏了清理器
and blew out the disposal.
好吧  别碰我的东西
Oh. Right. Don't touch the produce.
好
Right.
你不是要离开小镇吗
I thought you were leaving town.
对  我只是在帮着旅馆做维修
I am. I'm just helping out with maintenance at the motel,
埃弗雷特他爸生病了
you know, while Everett's dad is sick.
谁是埃弗雷特
Who's Everett?
你来这儿多久了
How long have you been here?
三个月  怎么了
Three months. Why?
一般人来到一个小镇
Well, you know, usually when someone moves into a town,
都会住到镇子里去
they actually, uh, you know, move into the town.
我也是啊
I did.
汽车旅馆可不算是小镇的一部分
A motel is not actually part of the town that it's in.
它那儿都不算
It's not part of anywhere.
我还没找到地方
Well, I haven't found a place yet.
我为什么要跟你解释
Why am I explaining myself to you?
你是个流浪汉或者杂务工
You're a drifter or a handyman.
我想我该走了
I-I think I should just go.
对  我觉得你该离开了
Yeah, I think you should go.
你好
Hey.
干什么
Okay, what?
-什么  -你为什么打电话给我
- What? - Why did you call me?
为什么你小声说话
Why are you whispering?
解释起来有点复杂
It's kind of hard to explain,
但是我正忙着清理吸血鬼老巢呢
but I'm sort of in the middle of cleaning out a vampire's nest,
我情势有点不利
and it's sort of gone a little sideways on me.
什么  你是白痴吗  迪恩
What?! Are you an idiot, Dean?
你还没笨到一个人去吸血鬼老巢吧
You know better than to go into a vamp nest alone.
我不是一个人  该死
I'm not alone, damn it.
行了吗  我不是一个人
All right? I'm not alone.
我有支援
I've got backup --
那家伙追查这伙人有一阵了
guy who's been tracking the nest for a while.
哪个家伙  盖思吗
What guy? Garth?
什么  不  你不认识
What? No. You don't know him.
是个朋友
He's a friend.
朋友  迪恩  你没有任何...
A friend? Dean, you don't have any --
你所有的朋友都死了
all your friends are dead.
我打电话不是想跟你说这些
That's not what I called to talk about.
索兰托  去  告诉老爸是真的
Sorento, go. Tell the old man it's true.
他听你的
He listens to you?
已经很久了
It's been a long time.
比起索兰托  我们的父亲更相信我的判断
Our father has come to trust my judgment over Sorento's.
我只听命于他
I answer only to him.
和上帝上床必然是有好处的
Well, sleeping with God has got to have some perks.
的确
Yes, it does.
去看看老爸还需要什么
Make sure the old man has everything he needs.
本尼
Oh, Benny.
我听到你回来了的时候
When I heard you were back --
不知道为什么  我就知道是真的
I don't know -- somehow, I knew it was true.
我只能相信  期冀
I had to believe it, to hope.
安德莉亚  发生了什么
Andrea, what happened?
老爸说他要吸干你的血
The old man said he was gonna bleed you dry.
我不知道
I don't know.
他改主意了
He changed his mind.
我昏了过去
I blacked out.
醒来时  我正从他手腕处吸血
When I woke up, I was drinking from his wrist.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这一切都是因为我  对不起
All this is because of me. I'm sorry.
不是  这不怪你
No. It's not your fault.
本尼  你从未对我有任何隐瞒
You never hid anything from me, Benny.
是我选择了你
I chose you.
但你为什么留下
But why'd you stay...
和他们在一起  和他一起
with them, with him?
为什么
Why?
你也记得最初的情形
You remember what it's like at first.
最初  一切都重新开始
First, everything resets.
活着就是吸血
Life is blood.
那就是全部
That's all.
-不管是谁给了你血...  -我懂
- And whoever gives it to you... - I know.
这很复杂
It's complicated.
什么事都很复杂
Every damn thing is complicated.
也不一定非得如此
It doesn't have to be.
安德莉亚
Andrea.
本尼  我没法杀死他  我们都不行
Benny, I can't kill him -- none of us can.
但是你  你死而复生
But you -- you came back from the grave.
你证明了他不是万能的
You're proof that he's not all-powerful,
他不是上帝
that he's not God.
本尼  他怕你  我知道
He's scared of you, Benny -- I know it.
你知道我回来是为了摧毁他的觅食方式
You understand that I came back to burn his operation to the ground,
阻止杀戮
to stop the killing.
做你要做的  我们就可以在一起了
Do what you came for, and we can be together.
他要我们带本尼过去
He wants Benny brought to him.
我知道我们分开了一年
I get the separate-lives thing,
但这可是猎魔
but this is a hunting thing,
我们得搞清这界限
and we need to find that line --
天啊  别说了  我已经把地点发给你了
Oh, my God, stop talking. I texted you my 20.
收到了  我这就去
Yeah, I got it. Look, I'm on my way.
听着  如果你们能处理好  那很好
And, listen, if you handle it, great.
我会请你朋友喝一轮酒
I'll buy your friend the first round.
但是  迪恩  听我说
But, Dean, listen to me.
迪恩
Dean?
迪恩  你在听吗
Dean, are you there?
迪恩  迪恩
Dean. Dean.
你在搞什么啊
You kidding me?
伙计  别这样
Oh, man, come on.
该死的
Damn it!
你好  父亲
Hello, father.
本尼
Benny.
我无话可说
I have no words.
别骗我了
Now, I know that ain't true.
能给我们解释一下吗
Can you help us understand?
我知道你不欠我们什么  但是
I know you don't owe us anything, but how?
你怎么会活着  站在我面前呢
How are you here, standing in front of me?
我找到了一条回来的路
I found a way back.
从地狱吗
From Hell?
据我所知  地狱在隔壁
Right next door, as far as I could tell.
隔壁
Next door?
那是什么
What's that?
我大概只能让你亲眼见识了
Oh, I think I'll just have to show you.
我知道这么说不能改变什么
I know it won't change anything,
但我很后悔杀了你
but I regretted having you killed.
一切结束之后
When it was all done,
我看着支离破碎的你  痛苦不已
I wailed when I saw you in all those pieces.
是不是  索兰托
Didn't I, Sorento?
我是不是哭得像世上最丑的孩子
Didn't I wail like the ugliest baby in the world?
是的  父亲
Yes, father.
于是你决定转化他的婆娘
That's when you decided to turn his cow.
可怜的家伙充满怨念
Poor so-so is bitter
因为你的"婆娘"地位比他高
because your "Cow" Outranks him now.
你为什么不让她死
Why didn't you let her die?
她对你毫无意义
She meant nothing to you.
但她是你的一切
But she meant everything to you.
如果唯一能从我任性的儿子那里挽回的
If that's all I could salvage from my wayward son --
是那个你为其抵抗你创造者的女人
the woman he defied his maker for --
我想要个能让我记得你的人
I wanted someone to remember you by.
你怎么会知道生活的价值
What the hell do you know about the value of life?
你是个吸血鬼
You're a vampire.
没错
Yep.
我觉得我们都清楚
And I think we both know
谁的同类杀死了更多人类
which of our kinds kills more humans.
从统计学来说  是你的
Well, statistically speaking, that'd be your --
是的  谢谢你  小卡
Yes, thank you, Cass.
我懂
I get it.
你是担心如果我们上去了  我会做什么
You're worried what I might do if we make it topside.
怕我会吃你的小猪猪
I'll start eating your little piggies.
我已经告诉过你  伙计  我被杀之前
I already told you, man -- by the time I got iced,
一直严格靠输血和吸捐血为生
I was strictly on blood transfusions, donated blood.
的确不是捐给我的
Not donated to me, I'll give you that,
但是我在黑市上花了大价钱买来的
but I paid good black-market scratch for it.
那是什么  吸血鬼节食法吗
So, what is that? Like the vampire zone diet?
听着  我想说的是
Look, all I'm saying
我开始看到人性的光辉了
is I started seeing something in humanity, okay?
看到一些不该被夺去的东西
Something that shouldn't be taken.
我吸血  但不吸人
I drink blood. I don't drink people.
我为什么要信你
And why the hell should I believe you?
你信什么重要吗
What does it matter what you believe?
你就真那么蠢吗  迪恩
You got your head so far up your ass, Dean,
都不知道我们已经完了
you don't even realize we're already done for.
天使知道
The angel knows it.
带着他这么惹眼的人  我们根本出不去
We are never gonna make it with him next to us glowing like a beacon.
要我提醒你谈好的条件吗
Do I need to remind you of our deal?
你承诺过的事
Of what you committed to?
他会害死我们的
He is gonna get us killed.
或许有机会检验你的话了
We may get to test that theory.
-又有怪物  -是利维坦
- More monsters? - Leviathan.
为什么你不飞走
Why don't you blip out of here?
它们太近了  我做不到
They're too close. I can't.
快跑
Run.
不  别去  狗狗  狗狗
No, no, no. Dog, dog, dog!
不要  狗狗  别烦那位愤怒的小姐了
Oh, no, dog, don't bother the...angry lady.
真抱歉
Uh, hey, sorry.
"狗狗"  你就这么叫它
"Dog"? That's what you're calling him?
的确名副其实
Well, it's accurate.
狗狗在打抗生素吗
Is Dog taking his antibiotics?
是的  没错
Uh, yes, he is.
它好多了  谢谢
He's doing much better. Thank you.
我得说
You know, um, I have to say...
我见过不少缝合的伤口
I've seen a lot of stitches in my time,
你的技术真不错
and you've got really good hands.
谢谢
Thank you.
对了  你觉得我很可怕吗
So, you think I'm creepy?
你的衣服都在军需用品店买  这是很可怕
I think it's creepy you buy all your clothing at army surplus.
白人至上主义者就这样
White supremacists do that.
说得对  可我不是
Yeah, but I'm not.
四处流窜的连环杀手也这样
Drifting serial killers do that.
有道理
Fair enough.
你就这么凭空出现  又行踪不定
You come from nowhere, you appear to be going nowhere,
还"见过很多缝合的伤口"
and you've "Seen a lot of stitches."
这些都绝对让人毛骨悚然
It's all pretty solid creepy.
你也不知道该何去何从  不是吗
You have no idea where you're going, either, do you?
对
No.
不是很清楚
Not really.
那是因为你没有可依靠的人
And that's because you have no one.
无牵无挂  对吗
I mean, at all, right?
所以你才会在这个地方
I mean, that's why you're... here in this place.
我有过一个牵挂的人
I used to -- have someone, I mean.
不过都过去了
But that's over now.
都结束了
It's gone.
你对此也有体会  不是吗
You know what that's like, don't you?
这是迪恩的二号替补...
This is Dean's other, other...
我猜你的起死回生
I suppose you coming back from the dead --
这绝对是叛变了  是不是
well, that's the definition of mutiny, isn't it?
这事让我觉得很疲惫
All of this has me feeling so...tired.
你本该放我一马的
You should have let me go.
可是本尼  我什么都不会放
But, Benny, I don't let things go.
是吗
Really?
你活了这么久  却怎么几乎什么都没有
You lived so long, how is it you have so little, hmm?
只有一架老大键琴和一窝土狼
Nothing but a beat-up old harpsichord and nest of hyenas.
大海是我的
I have the sea.
-我还有安德莉亚  -你没有
- And I have Andrea. - No.
你没得到她
You don't have her.
这我知道
At least that much I know.
那个蠢娘们
Oh, that dumb bitch.
你什么时候有了这种身手
When the hell did you learn to fight like that?
熟能生巧
I've had a lot of practice.
-你就打算这么坐着  -你说得对
- You just gonna sit there? - You're right.
我在这儿待得太久了  本尼
I've been here so, so long, Benny,
见过的结局和花样不计其数
seen all the outcomes, all the patterns a trillion times.
全都不值一提
It all means so little.
这个世界就是座绝望的坟墓  没别的
This universe is a pyramid of despair, nothing else.
挺悲观啊
A little dark.
毕竟  我是恶魔
I am evil, after all.
至少我还有这点悲观保持我的本色
At least I've had that much to keep me cold at night.
你从来没有  是吗
You never had that, did you?
凡事都要考虑  思量
Everything had to be thought about, considered.
苏格拉底有云
You know what Socrates said
不加思考的人生不值得过
about a life unconsidered.
是啊
Yes.
但就我们的本性而言
But what we have in us?
本尼  这不叫人生
Benny, that's not life.
这一点你还是不明白
That's what you still don't get.
所以你才总是痛不欲生
That's why it's always been so hard for you,
我可怜的本杰明
my poor Benjamin.
起来
Get up.
这是我唯一还能从你那儿夺走的东西
This is the one last thing I can take from you.
没门
No.
该死  你做点什么  再来杀我啊
You try, damn it. You try and kill me again.
你个小虫子  这是我的历史
This is my story, you gnat.
起来
Get up!
结局由我来选择  不是你
It ends the way I choose, not you.
起码我能让你看点新鲜的了  老爸
Well, at least I can finally show you something new, old man.
一个崭新的世界
A whole new world.
老爸死了
The old man is dead.
我们走
Let's go.
去哪儿  本尼
Where, Benny?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
去哪儿都行
Anywhere.
你不想离开  对吗
You're not leaving here, are you?
你从没想要离开
And you never were.
我们这儿什么都不缺
We have everything we need right here.
这种觅食方式依然天衣无缝
The operation is still perfect.
我们可以扬帆公海  一同掳掠
We can ride the high seas, plunder together.
我们能过上梦寐以求的生活
We can have the life we always wanted.
我只想把这儿烧成灰  一走了之
What I wanted was to leave a burning crater behind.
放下对你的回忆
I wanted to put your memory to rest.
我不只是回忆
But I'm not a memory.
本尼  我就在你眼前
Benny, I'm right here.
我爱的女人
What I loved --
早已逝去
it ain't here anymore.
她早就被像我和如今的你这样的怪物
It was snuffed out a long time ago by monsters like me...
扼杀了
like what you've become.
你觉得你现在比我强吗
You think you're better than me now?
不是
No.
我觉得我们都该死
I think we're all damned.
你为什么那么做  迪恩
Why'd you do it, Dean?
做什么
Do what?
让我复生
Resurrect me.
你可以把我的灵魂随便扔在哪个阴沟里
You could have drained my soul into any culvert,
也不会有人知道
and no one would have been the wiser.
你在胡说些什么
What the hell are you talking about?
你没事吧
Hey, you good?
兄弟  我不知道我算个什么东西
Man... I don't know what I am.
好极了
Oh, great.
我叫本尼
I'm Benny.
久仰你的大名了  萨姆
Heard a lot about you, Sam.
看得出来你们两个有很多话要说
I can see you two have a lot to talk about.